<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Laptop | Nihonhut]]></title>
  <link href="http://sulvaat.github.com/blog/categories/laptop/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://sulvaat.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-03-13T22:13:22-04:00</updated>
  <id>http://sulvaat.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[sul]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Fixing Ye Old' Laptop]]></title>
    <link href="http://sulvaat.github.com/blog/2012/03/13/fun-with-archlinux/"/>
    <updated>2012-03-13T21:40:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://sulvaat.github.com/blog/2012/03/13/fun-with-archlinux</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<pre><code>My laptop decided to kick the bucket last week. The HDD kept making clicks of death, screen flickered whenever the lid moved. I can't afford to buy a new one and I was starting to miss it hours after it died. It was time to put on the operating gloves and open this baby up!

First thing that needed to be done was a new HDD, had a spare 250gb that went in nicely. Next was the screen. I peeled off the sticky rubber stoppers from around the bezel which revealed four small screws. As I went about unscrewing them, I found that the top left one was striped - right from the factory! - China quality. I wrestled with it a bit and finally got it, a little dab of hairspray works wonders for small striped screws. The flickering was caused by a few shorts in the ribbon cable that connects the screen to the video card. With a soldering iron and a toothbrush I melted a few of the bristles over the exposed parts which resealed the cracks. It also smelled like toddler poop. Anyway, hit the power button and gave the lid a few swings, back in business. 

Now comes the fun part! Since the old HDD was now toast, I had to reinstall. Being slightly tech savvy, Linux was the obvious choice. I opted for Archlinux over debian. I have been working with Arch for a few months now and have really come to appreciate it's methods and it's community. At first, Arch can be pretty daunting because there is no default GUI. Being a long time fan of BSD, I was unphased and went about reading the &lt;a href="https://wiki.archlinux.org/index.php/Beginners%27_Guide"&gt;Arch Beginners Guide&lt;/a&gt;. It really is simple to setup and get going. Love it.
</code></pre>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
